Blue Dragon's Village
Awa Port
After leaving the Blue Dragon's village,
青龍の里を出た私達は
Blue Dragon's Village
何日も歩きながら休み 休みながら歩いた
we walked for days while resting,
and rested while we walked.
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
Blue Dragon's Village
Awa Port
Chishin
そしてついに...
Then, finally...
港町だ
It's the port city.
ハク ね あれは海
Hak, is that the ocean?
It's so beautiful. I've never seen it before.
綺麗 初めて見た
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
It's the Earth Tribe's Awa Port.
地の部族 阿波の港
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
First time.
Goes without saying.
First time, also.
またここに来るとは
I never thought I'd be back here.
O maiden!
otome yo
Flare up in the dawning sun!
akatsuki ni moeagare
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
Frail protected princess and live
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
That I've recently started enjoying
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
With strength and commanding presence
rinzen to tsuyoku
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
kedakaku sora wo miagete
And looking up idealistically to the sky
hokoreru jibun ni narou
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
mamori aishi tsuranuku
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
keshite ubawasenai
Like a noble flower
kedakai hana no you ni
With single-minded passion
hitamuki na jounetsu de
Even if faced with a cruel fate
zankoku na sadame sae
I will push through
kirihiraite miseru kara
Episode 17:      The Pirates of Awa
Thunder Beast, you've been here before?
雷獣 来たことあるの
Long ago. The geezer brought me here.
昔な 爺に連れられて
Ki-ja, is the Green Dragon here?
キジャ 緑龍は居そう
それが どうやら目まぐるしく移動していて
Well, he seems to be moving
around at dizzying speed.
キジャ
Ki-ja?!
I guess the dragons' powers aren't unlimited.
龍の能力 万能じゃなくて 限度を超えると 体力激減するんだね
After a certain point, they lose a lot of strength.
緑龍も探したいけど
I'd like to look for the Green Dragon,
but we're exhausted from our long journey.
長旅で疲れてるし 此処いらで食糧とか調達したいな
We should get more food too.
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
よし 行こう 港町
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Okay, let's go to the port city!
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
行かないよ あんたら連れては行かないよ
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
We're not going!
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
We can't take you guys down there!
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Especially not the one in the mask!
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
特に面つけてるやつ
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Clearly Suspicious
Red-haired Princess
Strangely Shaped Hand
Pat
じゃ 俺が行ってくるわ
I'll go, then.
町の様子なら なんとなく覚えってから
I remember how to get around the city.
ハク 私も行きたい
Hak, I want to go too.
姫さん 最近ブスになったな
Princess, you've grown uglier lately.
Hey!
ほら 何ということ 姫様はう...美しいです
How dare you?!
The princess is b-beautiful.
目の下にクマ
You have bags under your eyes.
手は傷だらけ
Your hands are covered with cuts.
頑張りすぎです
You're pushing yourself too hard.
You should get some rest.
ちったぁ休みなさい
なんのことだか 分からないわ
I don't know what you're talking about.
ハクはなんでも見通して悔しい
I hate how Hak always notices everything.
くれぐれも気を付けてね
Just be careful.
騒ぎだけは起こさないように
Don't start any trouble.
You guys should hide.
お前らこそ隠れとけよ
これ目立つから 置いてくわ
Oh, this thing will draw attention, so I'll leave it here.
It's so heavy.
おもっ
And White Snake...
それから白蛇
You don't have to tell us!
そなたに頼まれることなど何もない
We will protect the princess!
ま いいか
Well, whatever.
勘だが 彼奴はできる奴だと思うし
It's just a gut feeling,
but he seems to be a capable guy.
Hak!
ハク
Come back soon.
速く帰ってきてね
賑やかな町は久しぶりだな
I haven't been to a lively city in a while.
Because the princess asked me to.
I'd like to take a look around, but...
いろいろ見て回りたいところだが...
Because the princess asked me to.
Sir, why don't you stop by?
お兄さん 寄ってかない
Because the princess asked me to.
I need to get back to the others quickly, after all!
何しろ 早く帰らなきゃならんからない
気のせいか
It must be my imagination.
若干 町の連中の目に活気がないような
Everyone's eyes seem so lifeless.
Well, it doesn't matter.
ま どうでもいい
とっとと用を済ませて 早いとこ帰らなきゃならん
I need to do what I came to do and get back to-
No! Please stop!
や 止めてください
What? We're officials of Awa.
なんだ 俺らはこの阿波の役人だぞ
We're willing to pay the asking price.
言い値でお前を買ってやるって言ってんだ
悪い話じゃねぇだろう
It's not a bad deal, is it?
困ります 離して
I can't! Let go of me!
下種だ 下種に出くわしてしまった
Lowlifes. I ran into a couple of lowlifes.
What should I do, Yun?
And they're officials?
しかも役人かよ
俺一人の旅なら どうにでもなるんだが
If I were traveling alone, the consequences wouldn't matter all that much, but...
Come on!
Please let me go!
じゃあ こい
お許しください 誰か 誰か...
Someone, help!
Now I've done it.
やっちまった
口説き方が美しくないんだから 仕方ない
That wasn't a very beautiful way to seduce a lady.
I had no choice.
Wh-Who are you guys?
なんだお前ら こんな事して ただで済むと思ってるのか
You think you'll get away with this?!
You were rough with a woman,
and now you get angry?
女性に乱暴した上に 逆切れとは
美を学んで出直しておいて
You need another lesson in beauty.
どうした 何の騒ぎだ
What happened? What's going on?
やべぇ
Crap.
Oh, my.
あらら 逃げるよ おいて
Let's run. Come with me.
U-Um...
あの
Stop!
止まれ
You're in the way!
邪魔
Wha-
君 軍人さん
Are you a soldier?
かなり鍛えてるようだけど
You seem pretty strong.
No, I'm just a traveler.
いや ただの旅人だ
A traveler, huh?
旅人ね
あんたこそ その身のこなし 常人じゃねぇな
The way you handle yourself
is rather extraordinary too.
What? I'm extraordinarily beautiful?
え 尋常じゃなく美しいって
言ってねぇよ
I didn't say that.
さ お前は向こうを探せ
Damn it! Search the other side!
Got it!
はい
役人はまいたか
We lost the officials.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
もう少し君と居たいけど もう行かなきゃ
I wish I could spend more time
with you, but I must go.
Hey.
後はこのお兄さんに送ってもらって
Have this man walk you home.
Wait just a minute.
待ってこら
俺はそこまでこの辺の...
I don't know this area that-
居ない
He's gone.
なんだ 彼奴は
Who was he?
もう少し 静かに帰宅できないのかい ジェハ
Can't you come back a little more quietly, Jae-ha?
華麗な帰還じゃないか ギガン船長
That was a gorgeous return, Captain Gi-gan.
ひよっ子が聞いて呆れるよ
You're so childish. It's unbelievable.
目立って困るのはお前じゃないのか
You're the one who doesn't want the attention.
I was in a hurry.
ちょっと急いでたんだね
なんだい 役人に追われたのかい
Why? Were the officials after you?
それもあるけど もっとやばい奴らの気配がしてね
Yes, but I detected the presence of someone more dangerous.
Oh? You mean that thing you once mentioned?
それはもしやお前が昔言っていたあれかい
Yes. It seems the White and Blue Dragons have come to this city.
どうやら 白龍と青龍がこの町に来ている
What? You didn't buy anything?
へ 何も買ってきてない
Why did you even go into the city? You're useless.
もう 何しに行ったの 役立たず
悪い どうも思うような店がなくてな
Sorry, I couldn't find the right shop.
もう 雷獣じゃ話になんない
It's no use sending you, Thunder Beast.
明日は俺らも町に出るよ
Tomorrow, we're all going into the city.
Hurrah!
役人を殴った話は今は止めよう
No need to tell them just yet
that I clobbered those officials.
シンア もしやそなたも
Sin-ha, do you also...
I feel it.
感じる
あの海の方角に 緑龍がいる
The Green Dragon is toward the ocean.
キジャとシンアによると
According to Ki-ja and Sin-ha,
緑龍の気配はあっちの方に消えたらしい
the Green Dragon's presence disappeared somewhere over there.
俺はちょっと別行動する
I'm going on my own for a bit.
Huh?
I want to look at some weapons in the city.
町で武器とか見てんだ
俺しか分からんだろう 白蛇さま
I'm the only one who knows what to look for.
Lord White Snake, hold on to this.
これ預かっといて
なぜ私が
Why me?!
ハク
Hak...
昨日 役人に顔を見られた
The officials saw my face yesterday.
俺と一緒だと 逆に危ねぇしな
If I stay with her, I'll put her in danger.
じゃ 今日こそ 買い物してきてね
Make sure you actually buy something this time.
Sure.
雷獣 なんか変だよね
The Thunder Beast is acting strange.
Huh?
He's hiding something.
なんか隠してる
あのヨナべったりの雷獣が別行動なんて
Normally he sticks to you,
but he went off on his own.
それだけ皆を信頼してるのよ
It just means he trusts all of you.
そ そうなのですか
R-Really?
女に会いに行ってたりして
Maybe he's meeting a woman.
What?
Oh, it's around here.
この辺りですよ
あれ 海賊船だよ
That's a pirate ship!
What?
At the very least, it isn't a
merchant or government ship.
少なくとも商人や役人の船じゃないね
まさか あの中にいるってんじゃ
Don't tell me he's in there.
あれ
Huh?
What is it?
どうしたの
気配が
His presence...
消えた
It disappeared.
あれ 君
Oh, it's you.
It must be fate that brought us together again.
いややや また会えるなんて運命だね
ちょっと付き合ってくれないかな
Could you come with me?
Huh? No, I...
いや 俺は...
実は 追われているんだ
Someone's after me, you see.
役人か
An official?
まぁ そんなとこ
Something like that.
大丈夫 君に害が及ばないから
Don't worry. You won't get hurt.
Look, you...
って こら
昼間っからなんだ ここは
What are we doing here during the day?
It's easier to hide in these places.
こういう所の方が隠れやすいんだ
I don't have time for this right now.
つうか今はこんなことをしている場合じゃないんで
Sir, don't go!
嫌だ お兄さん 行かないで
Huh?
Th-That man could kill a woman with one look.
あのお兄さん 眼差しだけで女を殺せるわ
Really? Try it on me.
へ 僕にもやってみて
なにもしてねぇよ
I didn't do anything.
まっ いい女だったら 俺の里に山ほど居たからな
Of course, there were plenty of attractive women in my village.
なに それはどこだい
What? Where is your village?
Fuu-
風...
Uh, I mean, you're wearing some strange clothes.
あ..いや あんたこそ 変わった服着てんな 生まれはどこよ
Where were you born?
え 僕かい 僕は...
Huh? Me?
I was...
I was born... here.
僕は...ここ この阿波の生まれだよ
Here in Awa.
これは戒帝国からの輸入品
These clothes were imported from the Kai Empire.
港町だからね いろいろと手に入るのさ
It's a port city. You can get anything here.
Oh?
町と言えば この町なんか妙だな
Speaking of the city, this place
seems strange somehow.
一見普通だが どいつもこいつも 微妙に目が死んでる
It appears normal at first glance,
but everyone's eyes look kind of lifeless.
君は鋭いね
You're quite perceptive.
阿波の港は
The lord of this region, Yan Kum-ji,
has a lot of power here in Awa Port.
この一帯を仕切ってるヤンクムジという領主の力が強くてね
町の連中は皆 奴に怯えてるんだ
Everyone in the city is afraid of him.
I see.
国に内緒で やばい商売してるしね
He also conducts shady business
without the kingdom's knowledge.
やばいって
"Shady" how?
Let's just say...
さぁね
人の自由を奪うというのは この世でもっとも醜い行為だよ
that taking away someone's freedom is the worst thing you can do.
そういう奴らは腐って土に帰って
バラにでも生まれ変わればいいんだ
People who do that should rot in the ground and be reborn as roses.
君はそう思わないかい
Don't you agree?
まぁ 俺は人の護衛してる身だしな
Well, I'm a bodyguard.
なんて不憫な
How awful for you!
It's not so bad. It was my choice.
別に 自分で決めたことだし
Whoops, maybe I said too much.
しゃべりすぎたか
こいつがよくしゃべるんで
It's because he's so talkative.
僕には理解できないな
I can't understand it.
What a playboy
君達の護衛ならやってもいいんだけどね
Though I wouldn't mind protecting you ladies.
What a playboy
You're pretty particular about freedom.
やけに自由に拘るんだな
なにか嫌なことでも
Did something unpleasant happen to you?
僕はね
I-
ちょっとなにやってんの
What are you doing?!
Shock
Yun! Princess!
ユン 姫さん
Shock
What are you doing here?
なんでここに
や これは違いますよ
This isn't what it looks like.
こいつが無理矢理...っていねぇ
He forced me to...
He's gone?!
彼奴 どこ行った
Where did he go?
なに 真っ昼間からこんなとこ来てんのさ
What are you doing here
in the middle of the day?
お前らこそ なんでここに
What are you doing here?
キジャがこの辺りから緑龍の気配がするっていうから
Ki-ja said he sensed the Green Dragon nearby.
まさかこんなところだと
I wasn't expecting a place like this...
そしてあんたがいるとは
or to find you here.
いやらしい
It's indecent.
Don't get the wrong idea. I was...
あ 誤解すんな 俺は...
ハク
Hak.
こういう店に行きたい時は ちゃんと言ってね
If you want to visit a place like this,
it's okay to say so.
私ったら 気が付かなくて
I didn't catch your drift.
違う
It's not like that!
はい いいお言葉頂きました
Thanks, that's enough for now!
あぁ 彼奴め 一体どこに消えた
Where did that guy go?
That was close. I let my guard down.
危ないね 油断したよ
The White Dragon just appeared out of nowhere.
いきなり白龍が店の近くに来るんだもの
けど 白龍の他にも
But in addition to the White Dragon...
なにか強い 心乱れる者が近くまで
there was another powerful, unnerving presence.
やけに自由に拘るんだな
You're pretty particular about freedom.
Of course I am.
当然でしょう
The legendary four dragons?
伝説の四龍
守るべき主
A master I must protect?
くだらない
Nonsense.
生まれた時から決まった定めなど 僕の美学に反するね
Being destined from birth to do something goes against my aesthetic.
逃げ切ってみせるさ 定めから
I will escape my destiny.
Even if King Hiryuu appears,
I'll kick him away.
緋龍王が現れたって 僕は蹴り飛ばしてみせるよ
What?!
なんと
こやつめ 姫様に嘘をついて そんなふしだらな店に
He lied to the princess and went to a slovenly establishment like that?
I'm disappointed.
もう 見損なった
Hey, wait.
待ってご覧
Would you guys just listen to me?
お前ら 少しは人の話を
キジャ ユン そんなことダメ 言っちゃ
Ki-ja, Yun, you shouldn't say those things.
Even Hak wants to have a good time with women sometimes.
ハクにだって 女の子と遊びたい時くらいあるわよ
知った風にとんでもないこと言わないように
Don't say ridiculous things like you know what you're talking about.
静かに
Quiet.
役人だ
They're officials.
用が済んだら 早々に立ち去るべきだな
Once we finish our business,
we should leave quickly.
俺ら 目立つもんね
We do stand out.
ところが 緑龍は町にいるのか
By the way, is the Green Dragon in the city?
それがもう気配がないのだ
I can't sense his presence anymore.
Excuse me.
あの
あれ
Huh?
あんた 昨日の
You're the girl from yesterday.
はい 昨日はありがとうございました
Yes. Thank you for helping me then.
Hanging out where officials are
wandering around is dangerous.
あんた こんな役人うろつくところであぶねぇだろうが
仕方ありません
I can't help it.
私 ここで仕事してますので
I work here.
But...
しかし...
Stare
場所を変えるぞ
Let's go somewhere else.
Stare
What? You punched and kicked some officials?
役人を殴って蹴った
Yeah... though some other guy passing by
was the one who kicked them.
まぁな 蹴ったのはもう一人の通りすがりだけど
That was one brave passerby.
勇気あり通りすがりだね
You drew that much attention
to yourself, Thunder Beast?
そんな目立つことしてたの 雷獣
I was careful.
くれぐれも気を付けたさ
Oh?
この町の役人はそんな白昼堂々 そんな馬鹿な真似を
This city's officials do that in broad daylight?
はい 店で暴れたい 目を付けた娘を連れ去ったり
Yes. They trash stores and carry off women who catch their eye.
私達はなるべく役人の怒りを買わないように生活するしかない
The best we can do is to avoid
angering the officials.
どうして
Why?
ヤンクムジか
It's Yan Kum-ji, isn't it?
クムジ
Kum-ji?
この阿波一帯の領主だと聞いた
I heard he's the lord of the Awa region.
町の連中はみんな そいつに怯えてるんだと
The people of the city are all afraid of him.
はい 役人はすべてクムジの息がかかっているんです
Yes. All the officials have Kum-ji's complete support.
私達は商売の許可を得る代わりに
For permission to conduct our business,
we're forced to pay Kum-ji unreasonably high taxes.
不当に高い税をクムジに納めているんです
この町には不穏な噂もあるのですが
どうすることもできません
There are disquieting rumors floating around town,
but there's nothing we can do.
道理で 町の人達 元気がないはずだわ
No wonder everyone seems so depressed.
そうなんですか 私は賑やかな町だなと思いましたが
Really? I thought it was a lively city.
賑やかに見えるけど 笑顔がどこか嘘っぽい気がした
It seems lively, but the smiles look fake.
町をあまり知らない姫さんが そういうところに気づくのか
The princess noticed that, even though she knows nothing about this city?
海賊は
What about the pirates?
海賊
Pirates?
近くの海岸に それっぴい船が泊まってるんだ
There was a boat resembling
a pirate ship anchored nearby.
あんなのがいるなら 益々治安が悪くなるよね
It must make the city even less secure.
いえ あの人達が町の人に危害を加えたことはありません
No. They've never harmed the city folk.
Oh? Really?
え そうなの
確かに船を襲ったりもするのですが
They do attack boats,
but they only attack Yan Kum-ji's.
彼等が襲うのはヤンクムジの船です
例のものは
Where is it?
全て積んである
It's all loaded.
あとは 港にいる使いの者に渡すだけだ
Now we just have to hand it over
to the envoy at the port.
おい 見張り 近くに不信な船は
Hey, lookout! See any suspicious boats?
ありません
No.
そうか
I see.
海賊も今夜は我々の船に気づかなかったようだな
Looks like the pirates didn't notice our ship tonight.
あの
Excuse me.
なんだ 見張り
What is it, lookout?
さっきの 例の物はなんですか
What "thing" were you talking about?
Huh? Why would you ask now?
今更何を
It's a new type of drug smuggled
in from the Kai Empire.
戒帝国から密輸した新種の麻薬だろうが
そんな物どうするんですか
What are you going to do with it?
What are we going to do?
どうするも こうするも
町の連中に流して金を巻き上げるに決まってるだろう
Sell it to the residents of the city and make a killing, of course.
That isn't very nice.
それは悪いな
それは美しくない
It isn't beautiful.
見張り
Lookout?
Wha- Hey!
I forgot to introduce myself.
自己紹介が遅れたね
一時前から見張りを交代していた
I'm the beautiful newcomer who took over...
美しき 新入りだよ
the watch just a moment ago.
か 海賊だ
P-Pirates!
Sink it, boys.
沈めな 小僧共
To your posts!
配置につけ
Defend the ship!
応戦しろ
This power really is the best.
本当 この力だけは最高だね
I'll return the favor.
お返し
と 飛んでる
H-He's flying?
お休み いい夢を
Goodnight. Sweet dreams.
海賊ふぜいがよくも
Damn pirates. How dare you?!
Die!
死ね
なに 苦戦してるんだい 役人ふぜいに
Why are you having trouble
with a lousy official?
Jae-ha, quit playing around and help us.
ジェハ 遊んでないで 手伝ってくれよ
If you don't do it yourself,
Captain Gi-gan will sink you next.
自分でやらないと ギガン船長に沈められるよ
I can't help it.
仕方ないだろ 五年前までは俺 ただの漁師だったんだぜ
Until five years ago, I was only a fisherman.
つまり五年も海賊やってるんだろ
In other words, you've been a pirate for five years.
ギガン船長 ありましたぜ 薬
Captain Gi-gan, we found the drugs!
船ごと燃やしな 愚図共
Burn the whole ship, boys.
クムジはいないようだね
Kum-ji doesn't seem to be here.
役人はどうした
Where are the officials?
小舟に詰めて流して置きましたよ
We packed them into a little boat
and set them adrift.
殺しちゃいないだろうね
You didn't kill them, did you?
船長
Captain!
You're too strict!
いい加減きついっすよ
They're trying to kill us,
but you won't let us kill them.
向こうは殺す気満々なのに
こっちは死なない程度に痛めつけるなんて
あんな役人ども いなくなった方が阿波のためっすよ
Awa would be better off
without those officials.
どんなバカでもね 私はお前らを愛してるんだよ
I love you, boys, no matter
how stupid you are.
愛するお前らに人殺しの業なんて背負わせられるもんかい
I won't let the people I love
burden themselves with murder.
Mom!
お母ちゃん
好きだ
I love you!
俺も好きだ
I love you too!
I don't remember giving birth
to such ugly children.
お前らみたいな不細工 生んだ覚えないよ
Me too!
俺も
どうしたんだい やけに静かだね
What's wrong? You're awfully quiet.
あぁ ちょっと
It's nothing serious.
昨日から右足が疼いてね
My right leg has been tingling since yesterday.
どうせ気持ちいいんだろい
But you like the feeling, don't you?
A little, yes.
実はちょっと
Should I step on you?
踏んでやろうか
You're already stepping on me.
Thank you, Captain. I'm fine now.
ありがとう船長 もう大丈夫
You're already stepping on me.
今までこんなことはなかったのに
This has never happened before.
The soaring legs of the dragon.
飛翔する龍の足
古の力だというが 何度みても不思議なもんだね
They say it's an ancient power,
but I never get used to seeing it.
本当 ジェハの力は羨ましいよ
I really envy your power, Jae-ha.
It's so cool how you look like you're flying.
空を飛んでるみたいで 格好いいしな
一緒に戦ってて こんなに心強いやつもいねぇよ
There's no one else I'd rather have on our side.
どうせ頼られるなら 可愛い女の子がいいな
I'd rather have cute girls depend on me.
It doesn't mean much,
coming from a bunch of smelly men.
君達みたいな汗臭い男共に言われてもね
Shock
What did you say, droopy eyes?
なんだ このたれ目
Boo
You pervert!
You aren't cute at all!
Boo
素直じゃないね
You aren't very honest.
物凄く素直な人間だよ 僕は
Oh, I'm incredibly honest.
ただ むず痒くてね
I just feel uneasy.
ここは居心地よすぎるよ
This place is too comfortable.
十三年前 僕が里を飛び出して
Thirteen years ago, I left my village,
and after an exhausting journey,
I ended up here.
ボロボロの旅の末に辿り着いたこの場所
僕の能力を知っても 誰も気味悪がらないし
No one is creeped out by my ability, and they don't mention it to others.
回りにしゃべらない
本当 バカでお人よし
They're such kind idiots.
誰もお前にそんな興味ないんだよ
No one's that interested in you.
That's no good! You should be
more interested in me!
それは行けない もっと持って 僕に興味
まぁ とにかく僕は当分ここにいますから
In any case, I'll be staying here for a while.
置いてやってくださいよ 船長
I hope you'll keep me around, Captain.
お仲間が迎えに来てるんじゃないのかい
Aren't your comrades here to get you?
My "comrades"? You mean the dragons?
お仲間 まさか龍の
You must be joking.
冗談
Speaking of comrades, I wish we had more combat assets, honestly.
仲間と言えば こっちも正直もう少し欲しいね 戦力
いずれ あれの現場を突き止める
We'll track him down eventually.
その時には結構な戦いになるだろうさ
When we do, it'll be a pretty intense fight.
珍しく弱気だね ギガン船長
You're not normally so timid, Captain Gi-gan.
うちのバカどもを死なせるわけにはいかないからね
I can't let my idiots die.
どっかに若くていい男はいないものか
Aren't there any good young men around?
There's a beautiful young man right here.
いるでしょうここに 若くて美しい男
No, there is one! A good young man!
いや いる 若くていい男
お前はもういいよ
I've heard enough about you.
That's not what I meant.
I met him in the city.
そうじゃなくて 町で会ったんだ
へ そいつ強いのかい
Really? Is he strong?
I only caught a glimpse,
but he's crazy strong.
ちらっとしか見てないけど あれはやばいね
ほう やばいくらい強いのかい
Oh? He's crazy strong?
あぁ やばいくらい強くていい男だね
Yeah, he's crazy strong and handsome.
He's just your type, Captain.
船長好みだよ
Secure him immediately.
至急捕獲
Aye, Captain.
了解 船長
彼なら完璧だ
He's perfect.
僕の隣で戦うに相応しい
He's worthy to fight by my side.
待ってよ そういえば
誰かを護衛してる身とか言ってたっけ
Wait, didn't he say he was someone's bodyguard?
So what?
なんの 僕の口説きのテクならば 必ず落とす
With my skills of persuasion,
he'll definitely be ours.
Positive!!
明日になったら町に探しに行こう
I'll look for him in the city tomorrow.
You just wait!
待っててくれ
あっち こっち どっちだ
This way... That way... Which way?
Crying tears for the days that won't return
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
By the dawn
akatsuki ga terasu
(Gather, fierce arm)
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(All-seeing eyes)
(senri no hitomi)
Feet that dash through the sky
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
(Shield of eternity)
(kuon no tate)
Fulfill the ancient vows
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
O night, break into dawn
yoru yo akete yuke
Next Time
何の疑問もなく ただ言われるがまま
主を守るとか言ってるのなら
If you mean obeying orders without question to protect my master,
それは悲願じゃなくて 悲劇だね
that would be not my greatest wish
but my greatest tragedy.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 18:
次回 暁のヨナ 第十八話
Episode 18:
Ties of Destiny
縁
Ties of Destiny.